ANTHONY AGUILLON

PROFILE

Professionally qualified software engineer with over twenty years of experience in procedural and object oriented software design and implementation, four in industrial engineering, fifteen in finance. Accomplished in all areas of software development from architecture and design, requirements engineering to testing, documentation and deployment.

EDUCATION

October 2000 – December 2005

Berne University of Applied Sciences Department of Information Technology in Berne

Dipl. Ingenieur FH with specialization in Software-Engineering, Telematics and technical-scientific Computer Science.

WORK HISTORY

September 2006 - present

Software Engineer

UBS Wealth Management & Swiss Bank, Zürich

2006 - 2013

Design and implementation in the Market Data domain, mostly middle-tier services and database development, business logic and ETL, database design and programming. Implementation in C++ on Solaris, PL/SQL, SQL, Perl and shell scripting on Unix, performance optimizations in SQL and C++.

Design and implementation of services interfacing expert systems related to Product -Suitability/-Inventory and client information, document management systems and market data. Implementation in C++ and JavaEE, SQL and PL/SQL.

2013 - 2015

Integration of Misys LoanIQ client and server software into Syndicated Loans, continuous extension, maintenance and business support thereof. Interop with UBS payments, data feeds and ETL to or from TLTF,TEFIS,Market Data, GEAR, Cognos, Custom SSO, LDAP, Topcall. Implementation in Java SE on Windows Server, MS SQL Server.

2015 - 2016

LEON SIX project, as part of the ISO20022 Harmonization program, e-Bills: Technical Lead, Implementation of an e-banking/ SIX payments service component in JavaEE on Tomcat and RHEL. Additional work on specification, documentation and administration.

2015 - 2016

Front End Anomaly Detection FE-ADS, as part of the Multi-Channel Security MCSC program. Integration of BehavioSec Authentication with Behavioral Biometrics as a POC into e-Banking i.e. e-Banking reverse proxies, front-backend Payments Anomaly Detection System. Controller component spec.

2016 - 2018

Credit Processing – Collateral Delivery Team. Maintenance of Collateral application JavaEE server components, Misys LoanIQ, part-time administration, shared team lead role.

2018 - present

IDM-Process Transformation CH, Records Management CH. SME, maintenance and development of Legal Archives ELA/ ELBA. NGA (Next Gen Archive program) to eventually aggregate (and replace) 20 some archives including ELA, ELBA and LAZAR. Technical lead to (re-)design and implement ELA business processes in NGA as Document Services. Setup and tear down of everything Rigi in 2020 e.g. legacy routing and tactical migration.

August 2000 – August 2006

Software Engineer

mcs software AG, Bern Studer AG, Thun

Specification, planning, design and implementation of modules used in CAM software packages, CNC connectivity and interfacing modules, user interfaces.

Implementation in C++ on Windows, COM/DCOM.

KNOWLEDGE AREAS

Networking and distributed

computing

TCP/IP, UDP, MQSeries, Kafka

HTTP, Webservices

CORBA, DCOM, Java RMI, JAX-RPC

Programming Languages

and frameworks

(in descending order of

experience)

C++, PL/SQL, Java, C,

Perl,bash, Javascript, Python,

ASM, Prolog, Common LISP English as mother tongue

German as second language Conversational French

Basic conversational Tagalog/Filipino

REFERENCES

Natural Languages

Available on request.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Anthony Aguillon

Leimbachstrasse 229, 8041 Zürich anthony.aguillon@ubs.com